<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HTC</string>

    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_special_events">SPECIAL EVENTS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sunday__service">SUNDAY SERVICE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_marriage_service">MARRIAGE SERVICE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_marriage_intro">INTRODUCTION</string>
    <string name="specialEventButtonstr">PASTORATE TILL DATE</string>
    <string name="confirmationServiceButtonstr">CHURCH HISTORY</string>
    <string name="marriageServiceButtonStr">MARRIAGE SERVICE</string>
    <string name="HolyBaptButtonStr">BAPTISM SERVICE</string>
    <string name="confServStr">BURIAL SERVICE</string>
    <string name="MarriageIntro1">A hymn is sung standing during\nwhich the bride enters the church\n\t\t\t\t\tThe persons to be married\n presents themselves before the minister, the\n man standing at the right hand of the woman</string>
    <string name="MarriageIntro2">The minister says :\n\t\t\t\tDearly beloved, we are gathered here in the presence of god to join this man and this woman in marriage. This is a Way of Life instituted by God. and Holy Scripture commands all men to hold it in honour. Our Lord Jesus Christ blessed it by his presence at Cana of Galilee.\n\t\tAbout this Way of Life hear what our Lord says :</string>
    <string name="MarriageIntro3">\t\t\t\t\t\t\t*From the beginning of creation, \'God made them male and female\'. \'For this reason a man shall leave his father and mother and be joined to his wife, and the two shall become one.\' So they are no longer two but one. What therefore God has joined together, let not man put asunder.\'*\n\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tMark 10:6-9</string>
    <string name="Marriageintro4">\t\t\t\tMarriage is therefore not by any to be undertaken lightly or ill-advisedly, but seriously and prayerfully, duly considering the purposes for which it is ordained\n\n\t\t\t\tIt is ordained:\n\tThat husband and wife may give to each other lifelong companionship, help, and comfort, both in prosperity and in adversity;\n\n\t\t\t\tThat God may hallow and direct the natural instincts and affections created by Himself, and redeemed in Christ;\n\t\t\t\tThat children may be born and brought up in families in the knowledge of our Lord Jesus Christ to the glory of god;\n\t\t\t\tThat, marriage being thus held in hunour, human society may stand upon firm foundation.</string>
    <string name="marriageIntrBtn">INTRODUCTION</string>
    <string name="TheMarriageBtn">THE MARRIAGE</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayerBtn">PRAYERS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_mariage">THE MARRIAGE</string>
    <string name="themarriageText5">These two persons have come here to be made one in this Holy Estate. But if anyone here knows any just cause why they may not be married according to the discipline of the Church and the law of this land. Let him now make it known, or else for ever hold his peace\n\t\t\t\t/if no impediment is alleged/\n\tI charge you both in the presence of God, that if either of you knows any reason why you may not be joined together in marriage, you do now confess it\n\t\t\t/if no impediment is alleged/</string>
    <string name="themarriageText6">ALMIGHTY and Most Merciful Father, without Whose help we cannot do anything as we ought, we pray that, as Thou hast brought these persons together by the Providence. Thou will enrich them with Thy grace, that they may enter into the Marriage Covenant as in Thy sight, and truly keep the vows they are about to make; through Jesus Christ our Lord. \n\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tAMEN</string>
    <string name="themarriageText7">/MINISTER TO MAN/\n\t\t N, will you have this women, M, to be your wife, and cleave to her alone ?</string>
    <string name="themarriageText8">I Will</string>
    <string name="themarriageText9">/MINISTER TO WOMAN/\n\t\tM, Will you have this man, N, to be your husband, and cleave to him alone ?</string>
    <string name="themarriageText10">I Will</string>
    <string name="themarriageText11">/MINISTER SAYS/\n\t\tWho gives this woman to be married to this man ?</string>
    <string name="themarriageText12">\t\t\tAnd the parent or gaurdian puts the woman\'s right-hand into the Right-hand of the man</string>
    <string name="themarriageText13">\t\t\tif the parent or gaurdian is not present, The minister says:</string>
    <string name="themarriageText14">\t\t\tN and M, give each other the right-hand.</string>
    <string name="themarriageText15">/MAN/\n\t\t\tI N, take you, M, to be my wife, To have and to hold from this day forward; For better, For worse; For richer, for poorer; In sickness and In Health; To love, cherish, and protect, till death us do part, According to God\'s Holy Law; And to this I give you my pledge.</string>
    <string name="themarriageText16">/WOMAN/\n\t\t\tI M, Take you, N, to be my husband, To have and to hold from this day forward; For better, For worse; For richer, for poorer; In sickness and In Health; To love, cherish, and obey, till death us do part, According to God\'s Holy Law; And to this I give you my pledge.</string>
    <string name="themarriageText17">\t\t\tGod had heard your vows and we are witnesses.\n\t\t\tBLESS this Mangalasutra(Ring), O Merciful Lord, that he who gives it and she who wears it may ever be faithful one to the other, and continue together in love so long as they both shall live; through Jesus Christ our Lord.\n\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tAMEN</string>
    <string name="themarriageText18">\t\t\tThe minister delivers the Mangalasutra(Ring) to the man.</string>
    <string name="themarriageText19">/MAN/\n\t\t\tThis Mangalasutra (Ring) I give you in token of constant faith and abiding love, I honour you with my body, and all my wordly goods with you I share.</string>
    <string name="themarriageText20">\t\t\tIf the woman gives a ring to the man, she puts it on his finger, and holds it, saying the minister :</string>
    <string name="themarriageText21">\t\t\tThis Ring I give you in token of constant faith and abiding love, I honour you with my body, and all my wordly goods with you I share.</string>
    <string name="themarriageText22">THE MINISTER DECLARES :\n\t\t\tAS N AND M HAVE MADE THEIR PLEADGE TO EACH OTHER BEFORE GOD AND BEFORE THIS CONGREGATION, I DECLARE THAT THEY ARE NOW HUSBAND AND WIFE, ACCORDING TO THE LAW OF THIS LAND AND THE ORDINANCE OF GOD; IN THE NAME OF THE FATHER, AND OF THE SON,AND OF THE HOLY SPIRIT.\n\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tAMEN\n\t\t\tWHOM THEREFORE GOD HAS JOINED TOGETHER, LET NOT MAN PUT ASUNDER.</string>
    <string name="themarriageText23">\t\t\tthe man and the woman kneel, while the congregation remains standing. and the minister says :</string>
    <string name="themarriageText24">\t\t\tMOST Merciful and Gracious God, our Father, of Whom the Whole family in heaven and earth is named: Send Thy blessing upon N and M, whom we bless in Thy Name; that, living faithfully together, they may surely perform and keep the vow and covenant between them made, and may ever remain in perfect love and peace together, and live according to Thy law; through Jesus Christ our Lord.\n\t\t\t\\t\t\tAmen</string>
    <string name="themarriageText25">\t\t\tGOD the Father, God the Son, God the Holy Spirit, bless, preserve, and keep you; the Lord mercifully look upon you with favour, and fill you with all spiritual benediction and grace; that you may so live together in this life that in the world to come you may have life everlasting.\n\t\t\tAMEN</string>
    <string name="title_activity_marriage_the_prayer">THE PRAYERS</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt26">A hymn is sung; and the Psalm 67 and or 128 may be read during which the man and woman go to the Lord\'s Table. If the ceremony of the Saptapadi (Seven Steps) is observed, the people say or sing the psalm 67 pausing after each verse while the man and woman take one step forward.</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt27">Minister : Glory be to the father; and to the son, and to the Holy Spirit;</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt28">people : As it was in the beginning, is now, and ever shall be; world without end.\nAmen</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt29">*A Bible or new testament may then be placed in the hands of the newly married couple by the minister, with the words :</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt30">\t\t\tMAY THE WORD OF GOD BE A LAMP TO YOUR FEET AND A LIGHT TO YOUR PATH</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt31">\t\t\t\t\tThe following passage of Scripture is read :\n\t\t\t1 Corinthians 13 : 4-13.\n\t\t\tA sermon may be preached.\n\t\t\tThen the minister say :\n\t\t\t\t\tLet us pray</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt32">Minister : Lord, have mercy upon us.</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt33">people : Christ, have mercy upon us.\n\t\t\tThe Lord\'s prayer may be said.\n\t\t\tminister : Lord,save Thy servant and Thy handmaid;</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt34">People : And let them put their trust in Thee.</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt35">Minister : O Lord, send help from Thy Holy Place: </string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt36">People : And evermore defend them.</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt37">Minister : Be unto them a Tower of Strength;</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt38">People : From the face of their enemy.</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt39">Minister : O Lord. hear our prayer;</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt40">People : And let our cry come unto Thee</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt41">Minister : Let us pray.\nALMIGHTY and Everlasting Father, Who has given to mankind the Ordinance of Marriage, and dost hallow it with Thy blessing: Bless, we beseech Thee, Thy servants N and M, now joined together as husband and wife; and grant that, bearing one another\'s burdens, sharing one another\'s joys, and together fulfilling the duties of their home, they may ever be faithful to each other in love and obedience to Thy Word: through Jesus Christ our Lord.\n <b>AMEN</b></string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt42">\t\t\tO LORD and Saviour Jesus Christ, Who didst share at Nazareth the life of an earthly home; Reign, we beseech Thee, in the home of these Thy servants as Lord and King; give them grace that they may minister to others as Thou didst minister to men, and grant that by deed and word they may be witnesses of Thy Saving Love to those amongst whom they live; for Thy Holy Name\'s ake, Who livest and reignest with the father and the Holy Spirit, one God, World without end.\n<b>AMEN</b></string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt43">\t\t\tThe following prayer may be omitted if the woman is past child-bearing:</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt44">\t\t\tO MERCIFUL Lord and Heavenly Father, by Whose Gracious Gift mankind is increased: Bestow, we beseech Thee, upon these Thy servants the heritage and gift of children, and grant that they may live together so long in Godly Love and Honour, that they may see their children brought up in Christian Faith and Virtue, to Thy Praise and Glory; through Jesus Christ our Lord.\n<b>Amen</b></string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt45">\t\t\tO ALMIGHTY Lord, and Everlasting God, vouchsafe, we beseech Thee, to direct, sanctify, and govern, both our hearts and bodies in the ways of Thy laws, and in the works of Thy commandments; that through Thy most mighty protection, both here and ever, we may be preserved in body and soul; through our Lord and saviour Jesus Christ.\n<b>Amen</b></string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt46">\t\t\tIf the Lord\'s Supper follows, the service begins at the Breaking of the Bread, Otherwise, the minister says:</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt47">\t\t\tTHE Grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, and the Love of God, and the Fellowship of the Holy Spirit, be with you all.\n<b>Amen</b></string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt48">\t\t\tA hymn may be sung while the register is being signed by the Bridegroom and Bride. Two witnesses from each side should also sign.\n\t\t\tWedding march may be played and the newly weds go out of the Church</string>
    <string name="MarriagePrayertxt49">Medium Text</string>
    <string name="title_activity_english_service">ENGLISH SERVICE</string>
    <string name="sundayServiceBtn1">THEME/SCRIPTURE READINGS</string>
    <string name="sundayServiceBtn2">ENGLISH SERVICE</string>
    <string name="sundayServiceBtn14">TELUGU SERVICE</string>
    <string name="sundayServiceBtn15">PASTORATE COMMITTEE</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn16">THE PREPARATION</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn17">THE TEN COMMANDMENTS</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn18">THE LAW AND THE PROPHETS</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn19">WORD OF GOD</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn20">THE NICENE CREED</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn21">THE APOSTLES CREED</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn22">INTERCESSARY PRAYERS</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn23">THE SECOND LITANY</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn24">AN EXHORTATION</string>
    <string name="englishServiceBtn25">THE BREAKING OF THE BREAD</string>
    <string name="title_activity_english_the_preparation">THE PREPARATION</string>
    <string name="thePreparationEngtxt49">//A hymn or psalm may be sung or said//</string>
    <string name="thePreparationEngtxt50"><![CDATA[/prayer/\nALMIGHTY God, unto Whom all hearts be open, all desires known, and from Whom no secrets are hid: Clense the Thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of Thy Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love Thee, and worthily magnify Thy Holy name; through Christ our Lord,\t\t\t\t<Amen>]]></string>
    <string name="thePreparationEngtxt51">\t\t\t\tGlory to God in the highest, and on earth peace among men in whom he is well pleased. We practice Thee, we bless Thee, we worship Thee, we glorify Thee, we give thanks to Thee for Thy great glory, O Lord God, Heavenly King, God the Father Almighty.\n\t\t\t\tO Lord, the only-begotten Son Jesus Christ, O Lord God, Lamb of God, Son of the Father, that takest away the sin of the world, have mercy upon us; Thou that takest away the sin of the world, receive our prayer. Thou that sittest at the right hand of God the Father, have mercy upon us.\n\t\t\t\tFor Thou only art Holy, For Thou only art Lord, Thou only art most high, O Jesus Christ, with the Holy Spirit, in the glory of God the Father. Amen.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_ten_commandments">THE TEN COMMANDMENTS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_law_and_the_prophets">THE LAW AND THE PROPHETS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_word_of_god">WORD OF GOD</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the__nicene_creed">THE NICENE CREED</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_apostles_creed">THE APOSTLES CREED</string>
    <string name="ApostlesCreedtxt89">\t\t\tI beleive in God the Father Almighty, Maker of heaven and earth:</string>
    <string name="ApostlesCreedtxt90">\t\t\tAnd in Jesus Christ His only Son our Lord, Who was conceived by the Holy Spirit, Born of the Virgin Mary, Suffered under Pontius pilate, Was crucified, dead, and buried, He descended into hell; The third day He rose again from the dead, He ascended into heaven, And sitteth on the right hand of God the Father Almighty; From thence He shall come to judge the quick and the dead</string>
    <string name="ApostlesCreedtxt91">\t\t\tI believe in the Holy Spirit; The Holy catholic Church; The Communion of Saints; The Forgiveness of sins; The Ressurrection of the body; And the Life everlasting.\n\t\t\t\t\tAmen.</string>
    <string name="Lawtxt72">OUR Lord Jesus Christ said; Hear, O Israel : The Lord our God, the Lord is One; and you shall love the Lord your God with all your heart, and with all your soul, and with all your mind, and with all your strength. This is the great and first commandment. And a second is like it, You shall love your neighbour as yourself. There is no other commandment greater than these. On these two commandments depends all the law and the prophets.\n Mark 12 and Matt. 22</string>
    <string name="Lawtxt73">Lord, have mercy upon us, and incline our hearts to keep this law.</string>
    <string name="Lawtxt74">BRETHREN, we have come together to hear God\'s most Holy word, and to recieve the body and blood of the Lord. Let us therefore kneel and examine ourselves in silence, seeking God\'s grace that we may draw near to Him with repentance and faith.</string>
    <string name="Lawtxt75">YE that do truly and earnestly repent you of your sins, and are in love and charity with your neighbours, and intend to live a new life, following the commandments of God and walking from henceforth in His Holy way, make your humble confession to Almighty God, that you may be reconciled anew to Him through our Lord Jesus Christ.</string>
    <string name="Lawtxt76">HEVENLY Father, we confess that we have sinned against Thee and our neighbour. we have walked in darkness rather than in light; We have Named the Name of Christ, but have not departed from iniquity.Have mercy upon us, we beseech Thee; for the sake of Jesus Christ forgive us all our sins; cleanse us by Thy Holy Spirit; quicken our consciences; and enable us to forgive others; that we may henceforth serve Thee in newness of life, to the glory of Thy Holy name.\n\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tAmen.</string>
    <string name="Lawtxt77">HEAR the gracious word of God to all who truly turn to Him through Jesus Christ.\n\n\t\t\tCome unto Me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.\n\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tMatt. 11:28\n\t\t\tGod so loved the world, that He gave His only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth on Him should not perish, but have eternal life.\n\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\tJohn 3:16\n\t\t\tFaithful is the saying, and worthy of all acceptation, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners.\n\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t1 Tim. 1:15\n\t\t\tIf any man sin, we have an Advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous: and He is the propitiation for our sins.\n\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t1 John 2:1,2</string>
    <string name="Lawtxt78">ALMIGHTY God, our heavenly Father, Who of His great mercy has promised forgiveness of sins to all who forgive their brethren and with hearty repentance and true faith turn unto Him : Have mercy upon you; pardon and deliver you from all your sins; confirm and strengthen you to eternal life; through Jesus Christ our Lord.\n\t\t\t\t\tAmen.\t\tTHANKS BE TO GOD.</string>
    <string name="Lawtxt79">A hymn may be sung.</string>
    <string name="nicenetxt85">I believe in one God the Father Almighty, Maker of heaven and earth, And of all things visible and invisible:</string>
    <string name="nicenetxt86">And in one Lord Jesus Christ, the Only-begotten Son of God, Begotten of His Father before all worlds, God of God, Light of Light, Very God of Very God, Begotten, not made, Being of One substance with the Father, By Whom all things were made: Who for us men, and for our salvation, came down from heaven, And was incarnate by the Holy spirit of Virgin Mary, And was made Man, And was crucified also for us under Pontius Pilate. He suffered and was buried, And the third day He rose again according to the Scriptures, And ascended into heaven, And sitteth on the right hand of the Father. And He shall come again with glory to judge both the quick and the dead: Whose kingdom shall have no end.</string>
    <string name="nicenetxt87">And I believe in the Holy Spirit, The Lord, the Giver of life, Who proceedeth from the Father and the Son, Who with the Father and the Son together is worshipped and glorified, Who spake by the prophets.</string>
    <string name="nicenetxt88">And I believe One, Holy, Catholic, and Apostolic Church. I acknowledge one Baptism for the remission of sins. And I look for the Ressurrection of the dead, And the Life of the world to come.\n\t\t\t\t\t\tAmen.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_intercesssary_prayers">INTERCESSARY PRAYERS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_second_litany">THE SECOND LITANY</string>
    <string name="title_activity_an_exhortation">AN EXHORTATION</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_breaking_of_the_bread">THE BREAKING OF THE BREAD</string>
    <string name="title_activity_log_in_pastorate_commitee">logInPastorateCommitee</string>
    <string name="title_activity_log_in_pastorate_comite">LOG IN</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pastorate_comitte_main">PASTORATE COMMITTEE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_church_members1">ChurchMembers1</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youth_splash">Y</string>
    <string name="tv">YOUTH</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youth_main">YOUTH FELLOWSHIP</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youth_log_in">LOG IN</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sunday_theme">THEME</string>
    <string name="title_activity_responsive_reading">RESPONSIVE READING</string>
    <string name="title_activity_old_testament_lesson">OLD TESTAMENT LESSON</string>
    <string name="title_activity_epistle_lesson">EPISTLE LESSON</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gospel_lesson">GOSPEL LESSON</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bible_splash">BIBLE READING</string>
    <string name="title_activity_htc_lords_prayer">LORD\'S PRAYER</string>
    <string name="title_activity_telugu_service">TELUGU SERVICE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_developers_blog">DEVELOPER BLOG</string>
    <string name="title_activity_add_member_youth">ADD MEMBER</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youth_biblereads">Youth Bible Reads</string>
    <string name="title_activity_birthday_youth">BIRTHDAY\'S</string>
    <string name="title_activity_music_youth">MUSIC</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youth_members">YOUTH MEMBERS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_holy_trinity_church">HOLY TRINITY CHURCH</string>
    <string name="title_activity_church_history">CHURCH HISTORY</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youth_leader">JOIN US</string>
    <string name="title_activity_burial_at_home">BURIAL SERVICE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_burial_hymns">BURIAL SERVICE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_burial_at_church">BURIAL SERVICE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_burial_at_cemetry">BURIAL SERVICE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_telugu_nicene_creed">నిసెన్ క్రీడ్</string>
    <string name="title_activity_telugu_apostles_creed">విశ్వాస సంగ్రహము</string>
    <string name="title_activity_telugu_lord_prayer">దేవుని ప్రార్థన</string>
</resources>
